(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
白銀ノエル 2周年記念
Shirogane Noel 2nd Anniversary
#白銀ノエル2周年記念LIVE
#Shirogane Noel 2nd Anniversary LIVE
ギミーをお独り占めしてみたいので
I want to have "gimme" all to myself
ラブミーギミー
作詞・作曲：ryo(supercell)
Love Me Gimme
Lyrics/Composition: ryo(supercell)
今これ正しさが 君に暗示をかける
Now this correctness casts a spell on you
いいじゃんね
It's fine, isn't it?
軽く目を閉じてみて あたしがいいよって言うまで
Close your eyes lightly, until I say it's okay
そのままですよ
Stay just like that
余計なものは見えなくていい だってだって都合が悪いことだって
You don't need to see unnecessary things,
because even inconvenient things...
あるし
...exist.
秘密にしちゃいけないことくらい あたしだってちゃんと持ってたりするんです
I have things that I shouldn't keep secret too.
君をお独り占めしてもいいかな
Can I have you all to myself?
ちょっとの間だけ許してほしい
I want you to forgive me for just a little while.
まじまじ見つめてしまっているな
You're staring at me intently, aren't you?
穴が開いちゃうくらい見ているんです
I'm staring at you enough to make a hole.
どういうわけで今君は あたしの目の前にいます
Why are you in front of me now?
好き確認した温もりの血がで
The blood of the warmth that confirmed my love...
狙って伝えるから 覚悟しておいて
I'll convey it on purpose, so be prepared.
今言えないのは負け惜しみ だってだって都合が悪い日だって
Not being able to say it now is just sour grapes,
because even on inconvenient days...
あるし
...exist.
今日あくまで練習なんです きっとちゃんとうまく言えるようになるんです
Today is just practice,
I'll surely be able to say it properly.
君をお独り占めしてもいいかな
Can I have you all to myself?
常識の範囲で済ませるから
I'll keep it within the bounds of common sense.
ますます見つめてしまっているな
I'm staring at you more and more.
穴が開いちゃったらごめんなさい
I'm sorry if I make a hole.
まだ目開けちゃダメだよ
Don't open your eyes yet.
理由なんて聞かないで だってあたしえっとうまく言えない
Don't ask why. Because I, well, I can't say it well.
ラブミーギミー
Love Me Gimme
君をひとり占めしてもいいかな
Can I have you all to myself?
ちょっとの間だけ許してほしい
I want you to forgive me for just a little while.
いつも見てるのに気づかないから
Because you don't notice even though I'm always looking.
穴が開いちゃうくらい見てやるんです
I'm going to stare at you so hard it'll leave holes.
君をひとり占めしてもいいかな
Can I have you all to myself?
ちょっとの間だけ許してほしい
I want you to forgive me for just a little while.
まじまじ見つめるの薄目禁止
No squinting while I'm staring intently.
いいでしょ今くらい夢見させて
It's fine, let me dream for at least this long.
はい、みなさん、こんまっする〜！
Hi everyone, Konmassuru~!
はい、ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルです！
Yes, it's Hololive 3rd Gen's Shirogane Noel!
今日は団長の2周年記念ライブに来ていただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you all for coming to Danchou's 2nd Anniversary Live today!
いやぁ、もうなんか、ちょっと団長ね、1曲目からちょっとお疲れモードなんで、ちょっと息を整えさせてください。
Man, I'm already in "tired mode" since the first song, so please let me catch my breath.
大丈夫です、元気になりました。
I'm okay, I'm energized again.
いや、今日はね、たくさんのゲストさんも、あの、交えつつ、歌って踊って、
Well, today I'll be singing and dancing with many guests,
そしてね、そのゲストさんとたくさんお喋りしたり、MCしたり、っていう感じで、
and I'll be chatting with them and doing MC parts like this,
あの、楽しいライブにできたらな、という感じで思っておりますので、
and I'm hoping to make it a really fun live performance,
もしよければ最後まで見てくれると嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you could watch until the end.
ちなみにハッシュタグなんですけど、
By the way, about the hashtag,
白銀ノエル2周年記念ライブで、あの、ハッシュタグありますので、
we have the hashtag "Shirogane Noel 2nd Anniversary Live,"
そこでね、たくさん、スクショしたり、あと感想を呟いてくれると嬉しいです。
so I'd be glad if you could take lots of screenshots and tweet your thoughts there.
目指せ！トレンド1位です！
Let's aim for #1 on the trends!
1位になりたいです、よろしくお願いします！
I want to hit number one, so please help me out!
では、ちょっと団長ね、早速ゲストの元に行きたいと思います。
Now then, I'm going to head over to my guest right away.
じゃあ団長、ちょっと急ぎで... ちょっと喋りすぎた、やばい、ゲストさん待たせてるから、
Okay, Danchou's in a hurry... I talked too much, oh no, I'm keeping my guest waiting,
じゃあ、ちょっと行ってきます、行くぞ！
so I'll be going now, here I go!
待っててねー！
Wait for me!
楽しんでねー！
Have fun everyone!
ゲッターロボ！
Getter Robo!
ガンガンガンガン！
Gan gan gan gan!
若い命が真っ赤に燃えて
Young lives burning bright red
ゲッタースパーク　空高く
Getter Spark, high into the sky
見たか合体　ゲッターロボだ
Did you see the fusion? It's Getter Robo!
ガッツ！ガッツ！ゲッターガッツ！
Guts! Guts! Getter Guts!
三つの心がひとつになれば
When three hearts become one
一つの正義は百万パワー
One justice is a million power
悪を許すな　ゲッターパンチ
Don't forgive evil, Getter Punch!
ゲット・ゲット・ゲッター　ゲッターロボ
Get, Get, Getter, Getter Robo!
ガンガンガンガン！
Gan gan gan gan!
若い怒りが一直線に
Young anger in a straight line
ゲッターチェンジ　ぶちかませ
Getter Change, let 'em have it!
見たか変幻　ゲッターロボだ
Did you see the transformation? It's Getter Robo!
ガッツ！ガッツ！ゲッターガッツ！
Guts! Guts! Getter Guts!
三つの心がひとつになれば
When three hearts become one
一つの勇気は百万パワー
One courage is a million power
悪を倒すぞ　ゲッタードリル
We'll defeat evil, Getter Drill!
ゲット・ゲット・ゲッター　ゲッターロボ
Get, Get, Getter, Getter Robo!
ガンガンガンガン！
Gan gan gan gan!
若い希望が虹を描き
Young hope draws a rainbow
ゲッターフライト どこまでも
Getter Flight, everywhere
見たか 無敵の ゲッターロボだ
Did you see? The invincible Getter Robo
ガン ガン ゲッターガン
Gun Gun Getter Gun
3つの心がひとつになれば
If three hearts become one
1つの理想は 100万パワー
One ideal is a million power
悪を滅ぼせ ゲッタービーム
Destroy evil, Getter Beam
ゲッ ゲッ ゲッター ゲッターロボ
Get Get Getter, Getter Robo
イェーイ！
Yay!
あー、疲れた、疲れたね。
Ah, I'm tired, we're tired.
疲れてなーいですよ全然！なんで言ったんですか！
I'm not tired at all! Why did you say that!
いや今日は、ころね先輩来ていただきありがとうございます！
Well, thank you so much for coming today, Korone-senpai!
ノエルちゃ、2周年おめでとう！
Noel-cha, happy 2nd anniversary!
ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much. Thank you very much.
呼んでくれて嬉しい！
I'm happy you invited me!
いやずっとね、ころね先輩と歌いたいなって思ってたんで。歌って踊って。
I've always wanted to sing and dance with Korone-senpai.
しかも、ゲッターロボっていうね。
And with Getter Robo, too.
チョイス！完璧！
The choice! Perfect!
あー絶対歌いたいなと思って。いやでも...
I really wanted to sing it. But...
ちょっとね、今回こういうステージもご用意しましたと。
I also prepared a stage like this for this occasion.
これすごい！こんな...
This is amazing! This kind of...
こんなところ初めて来たよ。何にもねえじゃねえか！
It's my first time in a place like this. There's nothing here!
そう団長も、こんなステージがあったんだと思って。
Yeah, even I thought, "Wow, there's a stage like this."
これ何に使うの？何に使うの？
What is this for? What is this for?
一応、決闘場みたいな体らしいんですけど。
Supposedly it's meant to be like a dueling ground.
骨があったり骨が！
There are bones, bones!
怖いね。どっちが骨になるかと。ノエル...ノエル...
Scary. Wondering who will turn into bones. Noel... Noel...
え、なんかせっかくだからさ、ちょっと一緒にポーズしてさ。
Hey, since we're here, let's strike a pose together.
そうだね。スクショ撮ってほしいな。
That's right. I want people to take screenshots.
お写真撮ってほしいです！で。
I want you to take photos! And.
やっぱお写真といえば、多分みんなちょっとびっくりしたと思うんですけど、やっぱ。
Speaking of photos, I think everyone was a bit surprised, but.
ゲッターロボなんで、わーって。
Since it's Getter Robo, let's go "Whoosh!"
やるわよ！ちょっとそれ。
We're doing it! That thing.
やりたいなーって。ちょっとまってね。まってて。
I really want to do it. Hold on. Wait for me.
よしよし。どうしようかな。じゃあノエルちゃん前で。
Alright, alright. What should we do? Okay, Noel-chan in front.
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
一緒に。一緒に。
Together. Together.
よいしょ。じゃあ、いきます。じゃあこの...
Heave-ho. Okay, here we go. So this...
飛んでる！
We're flying!
あ、飛んでる！私ら飛んでる！
Ah, we're flying! We're flying!
飛んでる！シュッ！シュッ！
Flying! Swoosh! Swoosh!
でもなんか、後ろのさ、ちょっと感じが、なんだろレトロだな。
But the background has this... what's the word... retro feel.
いいね、今回。いい。シュッ！シュッ！シュッ！
It's nice this time. Nice. Swoosh! Swoosh! Swoosh!
ヤー、シュッ、あ、回る. シュッ. 危ない！
Ya, swoosh, ah, we're spinning. Swoosh. Watch out!
こんやられるからさ。
We'll get hit like this.
団長がパンチで！ジャスティスパンチ！
Danchou with a punch! Justice Punch!
やって。
Do it.
いきます。あ、じゃあちょっと、ジャスティスパンチ、ガチで行きます。
Here I go. Ah, then I'll do a real Justice Punch.
行きますね。
Here I go.
おらぁ！ジャスティス！
Oraa! Justice!
取れた？
Did you get it?
取れました。
Got it.
ちょっといい感じのところね。スクショしてください。
That was a good moment. Please take a screenshot.
スクショ撮ったかな？
Did you take a screenshot?
いやー。ハァハァ。ころね先輩大丈夫？
Phew. Are you okay, Korone-senpai?
ちょっとね、やっぱジャスティスパンチ、抜けた、抜けてないよ！
Well, the Justice Punch... it missed, no it didn't!
ジャスティスパンチをするにはね、やっぱジャスティスの心が必要なんです。
To do a Justice Punch, you need a heart of justice.
そうだね。大丈夫？汗汗。
True. Are you okay? *sweat sweat*
まだありそう、まだ残ってるんでしょ？
There's more coming, right? There's still more left?
まだまだ、残っていますよ！
There's still plenty more!
ぜひでは、今回ね、まあころね先輩1発目なんですよ、コラボ相手。
So, Korone-senpai is the very first collaboration partner this time.
そうなの？
Is that so?
そう、でまだまだ、いっぱいの？
Yes, and there are still many...?
いまして、次はなんと、おかゆ先輩！
There are, and next up is... Okayu-senpai!
おかゆ！おかゆ！おかゆも来んの！
Okayu! Okayu! Okayu is coming too!
おかゆも来ちゃいます。え、私もちょっと、あの見ててもいい？前で。
Okayu is coming too. Hey, can I watch too? From the front.
あ、もちろん！特等席で見てください。
Of course! Please watch from the best seat.
ヤーイ！じゃあまだ見てるよーと。
Yay! Then I'll stay and watch.
本当。じゃあこっちなんで、一緒に行きますか？
Really. Well, she's over here, shall we go together?
行く、行く！
Going, going!
じゃあ、レッツラゴー！次のステージまで行くぞ！
Then, let's-a-go! To the next stage we go!
ゲッタートマホーク！
Getter Tomahawk!
銀河の隅で 惑星はぐるぐる回る
In a corner of the galaxy, the planet spins round and round
電波の記録 エコーが返ってきた これで何回だ
Records of radio waves, the echo came back. How many times is this?
遠くの空で あなたに恋をしたんだ
In the distant sky, I fell in love with you
届かないこと わかってるのに
Even though I know it won't reach
ああ あなたに会いたいな って気持ちがループループする
Ah, the feeling of "I want to see you" loops and loops
あー頭がどうにかなりそうだ
Ah, it feels like my head is going to explode
それ以外考えられない
I can't think of anything else
あー今すぐ会いたいなって
Ah, I want to see you right now
幾度もループ・ループ・ループする
Looping loop-loop-looping over and over
この周回軌道上に
On this orbital path
あなたがいなくても
Even if you aren't there
トゥトゥルル・ドゥ・トゥトゥルル...
Tu tu ru ru, du, tu tu ru ru...
そこに大体、愛があるだけ
There's mostly just love there
トゥトゥルル・ドゥ・トゥトゥルル...
Tu tu ru ru, du, tu tu ru ru...
そこに大体、愛があるだけ
There's mostly just love there
声を辿って何光年だ
Tracing your voice, for how many light years?
延長線に消えていく
Fading away on an extension line
このままパッと忘れられたら
If I could just forget everything at once
楽だろうな
It would be so easy
触れられないのに見えてしまって
Even though I can't touch you, I see you
どうしようも無いやいや
There's nothing I can do about it
近くて遠いあなただ
You're so close yet so far
わかってるよ
I know that
あーそれでも会いたいなって
Ah, even so, I want to see you
何度もループ・ループ・ループする
Looping loop-loop-looping again and again
心があなたで鳴っている
My heart is beating for you
それだけが確かだ
That's the only thing for sure
それだけでいいよ
That's all I need
あー星が回るように
Ah, like the stars turning
僕らはずっとループする
We will loop forever
想いが軌道を描いている
My feelings are drawing an orbit
あなただけを追うよ
I'll only chase after you
あー今すぐ会いたいなって
Ah, I want to see you right now
命がループ・ループ・ループする
My life loops loop-loop-loops
この周回軌道上に
On this orbital path
あなたがいなくても
Even if you aren't there
それ以外思えない
I can't think of anything else
トゥトゥルル・ドゥ・トゥトゥルル...
Tu tu ru ru, du, tu tu ru ru...
そこに大体、愛があるだけ
There's mostly just love there
トゥトゥルル・ドゥ・トゥトゥルル...
Tu tu ru ru, du, tu tu ru ru...
そこに大体、愛があるだけ
There's mostly just love there
トゥトゥルル・ドゥ・トゥトゥルル...
Tu tu ru ru, du, tu tu ru ru...
そこに大体、愛があるだけ
There's mostly just love there
トゥトゥルル・ドゥ・トゥトゥルル...
Tu tu ru ru, du, tu tu ru ru...
そこに大体、愛があるだけ
There's mostly just love there
はー！
Ha!
おかゆ先輩、おかゆ先輩、来てくれてありがとうございます！
Okayu-senpai, Okayu-senpai, thank you so much for coming!
ありがとう、呼んでくれて
Thank you for inviting me
いやー、おかゆ先輩とね、団長ずっと惑星ループ歌いたくて
Well, Danchou really wanted to sing Planet Loop with Okayu-senpai
っていうのも、ガチでおかゆ先輩の惑星ループがめちゃくちゃ好きで
Because I honestly love Okayu-senpai's Planet Loop so much
うん、ありがとー
Yeah, thank you
ありがとー
Thank you
よもやさ、ノエルちゃんの2周年の記念に呼んでもらえるなんて、本当に...
I never thought I'd be invited to Noel-chan's 2nd anniversary celebration, really...
えー！？みたいな
I was like, "Eh!?"
いや、なんか本当にちょっと勇気を出しました、本当に、いつも...
Well, I really summoned a bit of courage. Really, I always...
勇気？勇気を出してくれたんだ
Courage? You summoned courage for me
来て欲しいなーと思いつつつも...
I was thinking "I want her to come," but...
えー！言ってよ言ってよー！
Eh! Tell me, tell me!
あ、ちょっともっと早く言えばよかった... ありがとうございます
Ah, I should have said it sooner... Thank you so much
どういたしまして
You're welcome
で、あれなんです、なんかさっきね、ちょっとまあみんな気づいたかわかんないけど
And, you know, just now, I don't know if everyone noticed...
バーって円になってる時に... うんうん
When we were going around in a circle... Yeah, yeah
団長、結構、結構ね、ちょっとチラチラっておかゆ先輩の方見てたんだけど
Danchou was looking, looking quite a bit, glancing at Okayu-senpai...
この「回る」っていうのも、実はおかゆ先輩がね、提案してくれて
This "circling" part was actually proposed by Okayu-senpai
そう、回りたいなーと思って
Yeah, I thought, "I want to circle"
ノエルちゃんのあと追いかけたいなーと思って
I thought, "I want to chase after Noel-chan"
団長、そのね、あの、おかゆ先輩のしっぽめがけて...
Danchou was aiming for Okayu-senpai's tail...
しっぽ、これね
The tail, this one
お互いこうやって、あー！フリフリ。団長何もないけど、メイスぐらいか、メイスぐらいだ
We were both like this, wiggle wiggle. Danchou has nothing, just my mace maybe
本当、あ、でもメイスお尻に刺せるからね、それ
Really, ah, but you can stick that mace in your butt, you know
あ、お尻刺し... ちょっととんでもないことになってしまいます
Ah, stick in the butt... that would turn into something outrageous
いや、来てくれてありがとうございます
Well, thank you for coming
どういたしまして
You're welcome
せっかくなんでね、ちょっとおかゆ先輩ともなんか写真を...
Since we're here, I'd like to take some photos with Okayu-senpai too...
うん。えーい
Yeah. Eii
きゃー！受け止めて、ギュッ、はー...
Kyaa! Caught you, hug, ha...
身長差がね、見て、確かにお互い...
The height difference, look, definitely both of us...
団長、ちょっと、あの後輩なのにノエルちゃんお姉ちゃんみたい
Danchou, even though you're my junior, Noel-chan is like a big sister
いやー、お姉ちゃんみたい
Yeah, like a big sister
こんな可愛い妹が、嬉しいなー
Having such a cute younger sister, I'm happy
はい、なでなで。え、すごい。団長ちょっと地べた、地べた？
Yes, pat pat. Eh, amazing. Danchou, a bit on the ground, ground?
あれ好きなんですよ、あのマリンの記念かな？劇場でそのおかゆ先輩みたいなね...
I love that, was it Marine's anniversary? In the theater, like Okayu-senpai...
猫ちゃんが寝転がってたやつ、一緒に寝転がりたいなーと思って
when the cat was lying down. I thought, "I want to lie down together"
一緒に寝転がろう
Let's lie down together
わ、でも冷たい！床冷たい！お腹が冷えちゃう
Wow, it's cold! The floor is cold! My stomach will get cold
あー、寝転がり、女子、女子会。あー
Ah, lying down, girls', girls' talk. Ah
何話すー？
What should we talk about?
え、好きな食べ物は？団長、牛丼ですけど、おかゆ先輩は？
Eh, what's your favorite food? Danchou, it's beef bowl, but you?
僕は...
I am...
ノエリちゃんかな？
Is it Noeri-chan?
あー！
Ahhh!
こういうとこなんだよな。
She's just like that.
そういうとこ...
That's exactly what I mean...
ぷ、すごいいな。
Pff, she's amazing.
プレイ、プレイボーイ猫。
Play- playboy cat.
プレイ猫。
Playcat.
プレイ猫だね。ボーイじゃないな。
A playcat, right. Not a boy.
プレイ猫。
Playcat.
ああ、さすがだなっていう感じで。
Ah, just as I expected of her.
なんかあっという間に時間が過ぎていくんですけど。
Time really flies, doesn't it?
実は団長この後あれなんです。
Actually, I have some things planned after this.
ちょっとまだまだ続くので。
It's still going to continue.
あの、おかゆ先輩には特等席で。
So, Okayu-senpai, from a special seat...
そう、あのセンターにもころね先輩が見てくれてるから。
Yeah, Korone-senpai is also watching from the center.
その隣でちょっと見ててくれてもいいですか？
Could you watch from next to her?
わかった！
Got it!
おっ、じゃあちょっと、あの、案内します。
Oh, then let me guide you.
こっち側に。
Over this way.
はい。
Yes.
ノエリちゃん頑張ってね！
Good luck, Noeri-chan!
頑張る！ありがとう！
I'll do my best! Thank you!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ああ、行ってしまわれた。
Ah, she's gone.
いやなんかすごいおかゆ先輩はね、本当に独特な雰囲気というか。
Wow, Okayu-senpai really has such a unique atmosphere.
ペースを持てて団長もまったりとしてしまったんですけど。
Her pace made me feel all relaxed too.
ちょっとこの後、団長ソロでなんとなんとね。
But after this, I'll be going solo, and...
今通常衣装なんですが。
I'm in my usual outfit now,
ちょっとアイドル衣装に着替えて。
but I'm going to change into my idol outfit.
あの、全力でアイドルをしようと思いますので。
I'm going to give it my all as an idol.
楽しみにしてて下さい。
So please look forward to it.
では早速着替えてきます。
Well then, I'll go change right away.
では失礼。
Excuse me.
じゃあ行くぞ！
Here I go!
よっしょ！急げ急げ。
Alright! Hurry, hurry.
Booo!
作詞・作曲：TOKOTOKO（西沢さんP）
Lyrics/Composition: TOKOTOKO (NishizawasanP)
また始まった 忘れん坊
There she goes again, being forgetful
手帳の隅っこだってカレンダーにだって
Even though I circled it in the corner
丸しておいたのに
of my notebook and on the calendar
どうして放っておく
Why are you ignoring me?
おかわりですか？
Is it time for seconds?
謝っても許さないんだからね
I won't forgive you even if you apologize
どこにでもあるような
It seems like it's everywhere,
どこにもないような
yet it's nowhere
幸せ探しはまだ始まったばかり
Our search for happiness has only just begun
楽しみにしていたプリンだって
Even the pudding I was looking forward to
君に食べられるために生まれたわけじゃなかったのに
wasn't born just to be eaten by you
なななななななな
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na
それちょっとだけちょうだい
Give me just a little of that
ねぇ一口だけちょうだいなんて
Just a bite, please, you say
あまりにも都合が良すぎじゃないの
Isn't that just a bit too convenient?
あっちからいらない
Saying you don't want it from there,
残しちゃったらごめんなさいって
then "Sorry I left some"...
君のせいかしら
I wonder if it's your fault
一体全体 分かつ証拠と
Exactly what is the proof of our bond
どれくらい愛してるって
and how much you love me?
言葉じゃなくて形で欲しいのです
I want it in form, not just words
今日が何の日か忘れてですか？
Did you forget what day it is today?
でも誕生日なんて言うのもちょっと癪ね
But it's annoying to have to say it's my birthday
もう知らない！
I don't care anymore!
結婚するとかしないとか
To marry or not to marry,
子供は何人欲しいとか
how many children we want...
幸せ家族計画を掲げる前に
Before drawing up plans for a happy family
タバコやお酒は控えるとか
Cut back on smoking and drinking,
明日から真面目にやるとか
start being serious from tomorrow...
だらだら続いてる
You're just being lazy
じゃじゃじゃじゃじゃじゃじゃじゃ
Ja-ja-ja-ja-ja-ja-ja-ja
それちょっとだけちょうだい
Give me just a little of that
ねぇ一口だけちょうだいなんて
Just a bite, please, you say
あまりにも都合が良すぎじゃないの
Isn't that just a bit too convenient?
あっちからいらない 残しちゃったらごめんなさいって
Saying you don't want it from there, "Sorry I left some"
君のせいかしら
I wonder if it's your fault
一口だけちょうだい
Give me just a bite,
もう一口だけちょうだいなんて
just one more bite, please, you say
甘え上手で罪なんじゃないの
Aren't you just too good at acting spoiled?
ちょっとだけちょうだい
Give me just a little
ねぇできたら全部ちょうだいなんて
Actually, give me everything if you can, you say
君のせいかしら
Is it your fault?
私のせいかしら
Or is it mine?
やっぱ君のせいかしら
I guess it's your fault after all
おしまい！
The end!
はい！はい、聴いていただきました。
Yes! Yes, you just heard it.
みんな、アイドル衣装の団長です！
Everyone, it's Knight Commander in her idol outfit!
はい、聴いていただきました、「Booo!」です。
Yes, you just heard "Booo!".
いやこの曲ね、すごい可愛くて。
Man, this song is so cute.
団長も大好きな曲なんですが。
I really love it.
やっぱね、ちょっといろんなホロメンがこの曲歌ってて。
Several Hololive members have sung this song.
団長もいつか歌いたいなと思っていたので。
I've always wanted to sing it too,
この曲歌えてすごく幸せです。
so I'm very happy I could.
しかも今日はね、なんとなんとこのステージ。
What's more, believe it or not, I got to perform on this stage.
ルーナたんのステージで、団長歌って踊らさせていただきました。
I sang and danced on Luna-tan's stage!
いや、すごい月がある。
Wow, there's a moon.
あれ？月が出てますね。
Oh? The moon is out.
今日、あっ、月が綺麗ですね。
The moon is beautiful tonight.
あらっ、ドキドキ。
Oh my, my heart is racing.
ちょっと一人だとね、一人は一人で緊張するの。
Being alone... it makes me nervous in a different way.
さっきはね、ちょっとまあ、あの、ころね先輩とか...
Earlier, with Korone-senpai and others...
おかゆ先輩とかと歌って踊って...そちらもね、めちゃくちゃ緊張したんですけど...
Singing and dancing with Okayu-senpai and others... I was really nervous about that too...
...やっぱ一人もやっぱ緊張するなと、今だに。
...but doing it solo is still nerve-wracking, even now.
今回ね、まぁ2周年のライブということで、まぁ2年経ったのにちょっとソロでもドキドキ緊張太郎なんですが。
This time, it's my 2nd anniversary live, and even after 2 years, I'm still Doki-Doki Nervous-Taro doing it solo.
どうしようかな、ちょっとせっかくアイドル衣装なので、ちょっといっぱい見ていただき...
What should I do? Since I'm in my idol outfit, I want you to see it a lot...
...リボンもこれ、たくさんね、見ていただいていると思うんですけど。
...and look at this ribbon too, I think you've seen it a lot already.
ちょっと今回ルーナたんのステージで、いっぱい見てください。
Please take a good look at it on Luna-tan's stage this time.
なんかお菓子がある。これ食べてもいいのかな？これ食べて怒られない？
Oh, there are sweets. Can I eat this? Will I get scolded if I eat it?
ちょっとケーキある。ちょっと食べちゃおう。えい！えい！
There's a cake. Let me eat some. Ei! Ei!
あ、美味しいな！美味しいな！何してんだろう。
Ah, it's delicious! Delicious! What am I doing?
あ！降りすぎ！降りすぎ！あ！やったー！
Ah! It's raining too much! Too much! Ah! Yay!
なんかめっちゃドーナツやらマカロンやら降ってる。いて、いて、いて...ちょっと埋もれている。
Wow, donuts and macarons are falling like crazy. Ouch, ouch, ouch... I'm getting buried.
え、ここ天国、パラダイスじゃん！あ、パラダイスあるか。いや幸せだな。
Whoa, this is heaven, a paradise! Ah, so paradise does exist. I'm so happy.
いやぁ、もう幸せ...あれ？ちょっと待って。今なんか聞こえた？
Ah, I'm so happy... Huh? Wait. Did I hear something just now?
はっ、待って、団長がちょっとスイーツパラダイスしてるときに、なんと、なんか声が聞こえましたね。
Wait, while Danchou was enjoying sweets paradise, I actually heard a voice!
じゃあ誰かが呼んでいる声がするので、団長そっちの方に行ってみたいと思います。
I hear someone calling me, so Danchou is going to go over there.
まだまだね、ライブは続きますから、ぜひぜひハッシュタグいっぱい呟いて、スクショも撮ってくれると嬉しいです！
The live is still continuing, so please tweet a lot with the hashtag and take screenshots too!
では、行ってきます！ダダダダダダダダ！
Well then, here I go! Dadadadadadada!
お、あれ？なんかね、ノエルちゃんと歌う予定だったんですけど...
Oh? Hmm? I was supposed to sing with Noel-chan...
あ、あやめ先輩！
Ah, Ayame-senpai!
あれ？ノエルちゃん？あれ？
Wait? Noel-chan? Huh?
お、お、なんか声がすると思ったら、あやめ先輩の麗しいアイドル衣装が見えたんで、急いで来ました！
Oh, oh, I thought I heard a voice, and then I saw Ayame-senpai's beautiful idol outfit, so I rushed over!
今本当はノエルちゃんって声掛ける予定が、勝手に出てきてくれた！
Actually, I was planning to call out to Noel-chan, but she came out on her own!
あれ？待って待って待って！うわわわ！
Wait, wait, wait! Wah wah wah!
ノエルちゃーん！
Noel-chaaan!
あやめ先輩ー！
Ayame-senpaiii!
ちょっとあの、興奮してちょっと歩き方を忘れてしまった。はい。
Um, I'm so excited I kind of forgot how to walk. Yes.
ということでね、一緒に歌っていきましょうか！
And so, shall we sing together?
はい！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! Looking forward to it!
お願いします！
Looking forward to it!
コネクト / 歌：白銀ノエル・百鬼あやめ
Connect / Vocals: Shirogane Noel, Nakiri Ayame
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made
目を閉じ確かめる
I'll close my eyes and confirm it
押し寄せた闇　振り払って
Brushing aside the encroaching darkness
進むよ
I'll keep going
いつになったらなくした未来を
When will I be able to see
私ここでまた見ることできるの？
The future I lost, here once again?
溢れ出した不安の影を
I'll tear through the overflowing
何度でも裂いてこの世界歩んでこう
Shadows of anxiety and walk through this world
止めどなく刻まれた
The time that has been
時は今始まり告げ
Unceasingly engraved now heralds a beginning
変わらない思いをのせ
Carrying unchanging feelings
閉ざされた扉開けよう
Let's open the closed doors
目覚めた心は走り出した
My awakened heart has started to run
未来を描くため
In order to draw the future
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if I come to a halt on a difficult path
空はきれいな青さでいつも待っててくれるから
Because the sky will always be waiting with its beautiful blue
怖くない
I'm not afraid
もう何があっても挫けない
No matter what happens, I won't lose heart anymore
振り返れば仲間がいて
If I look back, my friends are there
気がつけば優しく包まれてた
Before I knew it, I was gently enveloped
何もかもが歪んだ世界で
In a world where everything was distorted
唯一信じれるここが救いだった
This place was the only thing I could believe in, my salvation
喜びも悲しみも
If we share both joy and sorrow
分け合えば強まる思い
Our feelings will only grow stronger
たとえ大きな壁があっても
Even if there's a big wall in our way
超えてみせるから きっと
I'll surely overcome it
明日信じて
Believing in tomorrow
祈って
And praying
壊れた世界で彷徨って私は
Wandering in this broken world, I...
引き寄せられるように辿り着いた
arrived as if drawn toward it
目覚めた心は走り出した 未来を描くため
My awakened heart started racing to paint the future
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if I stop on a difficult path
空は綺麗な青さでいつも待っててくれるから
The sky will always be waiting with its beautiful blue
怖くない もう何があっても 挫けない
So I'm not afraid, no matter what happens, I won't falter
ずっと明日待って
Always waiting for tomorrow
はぁ…はぁ…
(Heavy breathing)
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
歌いきったよー！
We sang our hearts out!
あやめ先輩、いらっしゃいませ！
Ayame-senpai, welcome!
2周年おめでとうございます！
Happy 2nd Anniversary!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
あやめ先輩と歌って踊って、すごく嬉しいです！
I'm so happy I got to sing and dance with Ayame-senpai!
緊張しちゃってドキドキ…
I was so nervous, my heart was racing...
なんかちょっとあれだよね、V-ARK以来だよね。
It's been a while, hasn't it? Since V-ARK.
一緒に歌ったのは。
Since we last sang together.
V-ARKの時はね、やっぱり団長、
Back at V-ARK, Danchou was...
あやめ先輩が歌ってる時は、こうやって「うわぁー！」って応援してて。
cheering like "Waaah!" from the side while Ayame-senpai sang.
逆に団長が歌ってる時は、余が「うわぁー！」ってやってたから。
And when Danchou was singing, I was also like "Waaah!"
今回こう、ステージ一緒で歌うっていうのはすごい憧れてたんで。
I really looked forward to being on the same stage and singing together.
今回一緒に歌えて嬉しいです。ドキドキ。
I'm so happy we could sing together. I'm so excited.
ドキドキ、ドキドキ。
Pounding, pounding.
あ、ちょっといい写真が撮れそう。
Oh, it looks like we can take a good photo.
いっぱいスクショして、ハッシュタグぜひぜひお願いします！
Take lots of screenshots and use the hashtag, please!
ツイートしてね！
Please tweet them!
撮ってね！
Take photos, okay!
なんかやっぱ思った、身長差がすごいんだよね。
I just noticed, the height difference is huge.
あ、なんか思った。余がなんかちっちゃい、ちっちゃい。
Yeah, I thought so too. Ojou is so small and cute.
やっぱホロメン、ちっちゃい子多いけど、なんか団長お姉ちゃんになっちゃうな、本当に。
There are many small members in Hololive, but Danchou really feels like a big sister.
あ！じゃあ余が妹！
Oh! Then Ojou is my little sister!
あれあれあれ！落ち着いて！
Wait, wait, wait! Calm down!
あ、でも確かにあれだね。よくよく見てみると…
Wait, looking closely at our outfits...
アイドル衣装が、なんか同じタイプの形が同じ。
They are the same type! The silhouette is identical.
形ですね！あらー、本当に！しかも赤と青っていうね。
It's true! And we have red and blue, a perfect contrast.
相性がいいんじゃないですか？
Isn't this a great match? The chemistry is good.
ふりふり、ふりふり。
Wiggle, wiggle, wiggle.
抱きしめてもいいですか？
Can I give you a hug?
あー、よしよしよし。
Oh, so cute. There, there, there.
あーいい匂い。
You smell good.
でもちょっと痛いな、角が。ちょっと刺さるな。
But the horns are a bit painful, they're poking me.
血まみれになってしまう。
I'm going to end up covered in blood.
いや本当に今日コネクト一緒に歌わせていただき本当にありがとうございました。
Anyway, thank you so much for singing Connect with me today.
ありがとうございました。余もね、大好きな曲なんで嬉しいです。
Thank you! I love this song, so I'm really happy.
歌枠とかでも結構歌ってて、好きなの。
I've sung it in karaoke streams before because I like it so much.
あやめ先輩のコネクトに団長も混ざりたいなと思ってお邪魔したんですけど。
I really wanted to join in when Ayame-senpai sang it, so I barged in this time.
え、2周年の場でいいんですか？
Was it okay for me to be here for your 2nd anniversary?
いやもう、むしろむしろですよ。
Of course! I'm the one who's grateful.
この後、なんと団長、かなたんと歌って踊るんですけど。
After this, Danchou will be singing and dancing with Kanatan!
コネクトにちょっと繋がるというか、関係のある曲を歌おうかなと思っております。
And it's a song that's somewhat related to Connect...
あー、じゃああの曲が流れるのかな。わかるかなー。
Oh, I wonder which song it is? Do you know?
ちょっとかなたんにバトンタッチして。
I'll pass the baton to Kanatan now.
ぜひぜひ見ておこうと思うので
I'm definitely going to watch you.
いやいや、もう特等席にある、後ろとは言わず
No, no, it's the best seat! Don't say it's in the back.
あ、あそこ、あそこで、ど真ん中で
Ah, right there, right there in the center!
ぜひぜひ見ていく、ペンライト振ってくるわ
I'll definitely be watching and waving my penlight!
本当？じゃあ頑張ってね、ありがとう
Really? Then good luck! Thank you.
ばいばーい！
Bye-bye!
いやちょっと、あやめ先輩も応援してくれているということで、
Well, since Ayame-senpai is cheering me on,
団長もちょっと次の曲、かなたんと楽しんで歌いたいと思います。
I'd like to enjoy singing the next song with Kanatan.
ルミナス / 歌：天音かなた・白銀ノエル
Luminous / Vocals: Amane Kanata, Shirogane Noel
伝えあった心の温度
The temperature of our hearts that we shared,
そっと大事に抱え歩いていた
I walked while gently holding it close.
答えのない願いの中で
Within a wish that has no answer,
言葉は未来変えて
Words will change the future.
幼い頃ずっと夢に見ていた
The thing I've always dreamed of since I was young,
私にはまだ遠いけど
It's still far away for me, but...
君がいれば
If you are here...
少しは強くなれる気がして
I feel like I can become a little stronger,
明日の色を重ね塗った
So I layered the colors of tomorrow.
呼んだ希望たどって 止めた世界を超えた
Following the hope I called out, I surpassed the frozen world.
諦めない思い いつか心繋げた
Feelings that won't give up eventually connected our hearts.
泣いてたって笑って 明日迎えに行こう
Even if we were crying, let's smile and go meet tomorrow.
決めた誓いつないで 倒れても
Holding onto the vow we made, even if we fall,
君の心を 守るため
It's all to protect your heart.
記憶のない時の流れに
In the flow of time without memory,
きっと求めていた暖かさはあって
The warmth I was seeking must have been there.
包まれた瞬間すべての
The moment I was enveloped, all my
思いは君へ巡る
Thoughts came around to you.
空に向かって 走り手にした
I ran towards the sky and grasped
いくつもの尊い光 胸にしまって
Many precious lights, and kept them in my heart.
私の中の 輝きに変え
Transforming them into a radiance within me,
迷いを全部払って飛ぼう
Let's brush aside all hesitation and fly.
世界の見えない 入り組んだ迷路を抜け
Escaping from the world's invisible, intricate maze,
君が流した涙で 心目覚めた
My heart awakened through the tears you shed.
そして知った世界は こんなにもまだ綺麗で
And I realized that the world is still so beautiful,
新しい可能性を 生むだろう
It will surely give birth to new possibilities.
時のかけらの 願いから
From a wish in a fragment of time.
救い信じて 忘れた思い
Believing in salvation, the feelings I forgot,
私が始まりに立って
I will stand at the beginning.
君の笑顔 取り戻すよ
I'll get your smile back,
真実も奇跡になった
The truth has also become a miracle.
呼んだ希望たどって 止めた世界を超えた
Following the hope I called out, I surpassed the frozen world.
諦めない思い いつか心繋げた
Feelings that won't give up eventually connected our hearts.
泣いてたって笑って 明日迎えに行こう
Even if we were crying, let's smile and go meet tomorrow.
決めた誓いつないで 倒れても
Holding onto the vow we made, even if we fall,
君の心を 守るため
It's all to protect your heart.
君の そばにいよう
I'll be by your side.
はーい！
Yay!
かなたん！かなたん！かなたん！
Kanatan! Kanatan! Kanatan!
かっこよかったです、2周年！
That was so cool! Happy 2nd anniversary!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！そしてお呼びいただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you! And thank you for having me here!
いえいえいえ、今日はちょっとね、お忙しい中来ていただいて。
No, no, thank you for coming despite your busy schedule today.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
でもかなたんね、いつも団長、最近でもかなたんの配信も...最近っていうか結構前から見てるけど、
But Kanata, I've been watching your streams for a while now, even recently...
嬉しい！見ててくれるの？
I'm so happy! You watch them?
そう、かなたんの配信お気に入りなんだけど、なんかね、
Yeah, your streams are my favorite, but you know,
やっぱ最近肉叩いてるイメージもあるし、
I've had this image of you punching meat lately,
マイクラしたり、なんか色んなこと頑張ってるから大丈夫？忙しくないかなと思って。
and with Minecraft and everything, are you okay? I was worried you might be too busy.
いや全然大丈夫ですよ！僕はやっぱり団長との約束、
No, I'm perfectly fine! I still remember my promise to you, Danchou.
早くこのご時世、ちょっと落ち着いたら、
Once things in the world settle down a bit,
遊びに行くぞー！ うわー！目の前に行くぞー！
We're going to hang out! Whoa! I'm coming to see you!
嬉しい！かなたんとこうやってアイドル衣装で並んでるけど、
I'm so happy! Here we are standing together in our idol outfits,
かなたんとは実はBloomでMCを担当したことがあって、
but Kanata and I actually hosted the MC together at Bloom.
そうなんですよ！MCをご一緒に。
That's right! We did the MC together.
懐かしいなと思いながら...ちょっと今グリグリ痛いんだよねそれ！
I was feeling nostalgic... wait, that really hurts right now!
ちょっと待って！痛い！出血するんですけど！
Wait a minute! It hurts! I'm going to bleed!
やばいやばい！脳みそから血が出ちゃう！
Oh no, oh no! Blood's coming out of my brain!
怖い怖い！
Scary, scary!
かなたん、その時はあんまりスクショタイムとかでバババって写真撮れなかったから、
Kanata, back then we didn't really have a screenshot time to take lots of photos,
今回は写真をいっぱい撮りたいなと思って！
so I wanted to take plenty of pictures this time!
あーいいですね！撮りましょう！
Oh, that's a great idea! Let's do it!
どんな感じ？どんな感じ？
What kind of pose? What kind of pose?
やっぱり二人仲良しみたいな感じのが撮りたいな！
I'd like to take one where we look like close friends!
じゃあこんな感じで！
Okay, then how about this!
あれ？仲良し...喧嘩してね？
Wait? Close friends... aren't we fighting?
あれ？こんな感じかな？
Huh? Is it like this?
仲良くって言ってるじゃん！こらこら！
I said "close friends"! Hey now!
餌だよ。お姉さん釣れないよ。
It's bait. You can't catch this big sister.
やだ！痛い痛い！
No! It hurts, it hurts!
ちょっと負傷してしまった。団長血まみれになってしまう！
I've been injured. Danchou is going to be covered in blood!
いや、あれだね。団長、この負傷したところで次があるんだよね！
Well, anyway. Danchou, even with those injuries, you have something next!
実は。マジで？傷も癒えぬうちに。
Actually. Seriously? Before the wounds even heal.
傷も癒えぬ中、じゃあ一緒にここから捌けようか！
Wounds and all, let's leave the stage together!
次のステージに行きましょう！
Let's head to the next stage!
行きましょう！
Let's go!
こんな感じでいいのかな？
Is this okay?
こんな感じで捌け。じゃあ次は楽しみに！
Exiting like this. Well then, look forward to the next part!
準備してくるね！ 行ってくるで！行ってくるで！
I'll go get ready! I'm off! I'm off!
僕は帰るんで。
I'm heading home.
朝起きて 歯を磨いて
Wake up in the morning, brush my teeth
あっという間 午後十時
And in no time, it's 10 PM
今日もたくさん 笑ったなあ
I laughed a lot today too
たくさんときめいたなあ
My heart fluttered a lot too
友達と バカみたいに 騒いでる時にも
Even when I'm messing around like an idiot with my friends
チラチラって 目が合う
Our eyes meet for a split second
偶然だよね?
It's just a coincidence, right?
初恋なんて 言えない
I can't say it's my first love
キャラじゃないんだもん
It's just not like me
ねぇ 明日も 会えるよね?
Hey, we'll meet again tomorrow, right?
まぶたを閉じると キラキラ君だらけ
When I close my eyelids, it's sparkling full of you
今日も楽しかったね
Today was fun too, wasn't it?
ああ 恋してんだなあ
Ah, I guess I'm in love
おやすみって メールして
I sent a text saying "goodnight"
返事待ち 一時間
Waiting for a reply for an hour
やっぱ脈は ないのかな
I guess there's no chance after all
ひたすら受信ボタン
Constantly hitting the refresh button
君のメール 絵文字つき
Your text had emojis
ゆらゆらハートマーク
A swaying heart symbol
期待していいのかな
Can I let myself hope?
眠れなくなる
I won't be able to sleep
君のそばにいると 楽しすぎるんだ
When I'm by your side, it's just too much fun
ねぇ 運命なのですか?
Hey, is this destiny?
生まれて初めて ふわふわ恋心
For the first time in my life, a fluffy feeling of love
いつか言いたいな
I want to say it someday
ねぇ 大好きだよ
Hey, I love you
もう少しで 朝が来るよ
Morning will be here soon
そろそろ
It's almost time...
...寝なくちゃだよね
...I have to go to sleep.
また明日ね 電話するよ
See you tomorrow, I'll call you.
やっぱ寂しいよ
I'm lonely after all.
もっともっと隣にいたいから
Because I want to be by your side more and more.
カッコいいなんて言えない
I can't say I'm cool.
キャラじゃないんだもん
It's not my character.
ねえ 明日も会えるよね
Hey, we can meet again tomorrow, right?
まぶたを閉じると
When I close my eyelids,
キラキラ 君だらけ
Everything's sparkling with you.
今日楽しかったね
Today was fun, wasn't it?
あー 恋してんだなー
Ah, I'm in love.
嬉しいな 嬉しいな
I'm so happy, I'm so happy.
はじめまして 恋心
Nice to meet you, my feelings of love.
明日また会えるね
We can meet again tomorrow.
おやすみなさい
Good night.
夢ですぐ会えるね
We'll meet soon in our dreams.
おやすみなさい
Good night.
あー！あー！あー！
Ahhh! Ahhh! Ahhh!
なんかお尻が温かくて寝過ごしちゃったな。
My butt was so warm that I overslept.
あ、やばい。
Oh, that's bad.
星って、ちなみに月って温かいのかな。温かいよね。
Are stars... or rather, the moon, warm? It's warm, right?
熱いくらいですよ。
It's almost hot.
熱いんですか。寝過ごしちゃった。
It's hot? We overslept.
いや、今日、ちょっとあれだね。ラミィ来てくれてありがとうございます。
Well, today's been something. Lamy, thank you for coming.
はい！ノエル先輩二周年おめでとうございまーす！
Yes! Noel-senpai, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary!
イエーイ、ありがとうございます！つっつっつー！
Yay, thank you! Tsu-tsu-tsu!
つっつっつー！
Tsu-tsu-tsu!
でもね、あんまりね、ちょっと暴れすぎるとこのマカロンから落ちてしまうんで。
But you know, if we move around too much, we'll fall off this macaron.
はい。
Yes.
このステージはちょっとルーナたんのステージなんだけど、お世話に今日いっぱいなってて。
This stage is actually Luna-tan's stage, but we're using it a lot today.
可愛い。
So cute.
でもね、マカロンの上に乗るのはちょっと今回初めて。
But this is the first time I've ever stood on a macaron.
初めてですね。これラミィも初めて。
It's the first time. It's Lamy's first time too.
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
ちょ、皆さんやめて、ね、我々土足だからね。
Hey, everyone stop it. We're wearing shoes, you know.
大丈夫？ちょっとお腹壊しちゃう。ポポも壊しちゃう。
Is it okay? You'll get a stomachache. Popo will get one too.
なあ、美味しい。
But it's delicious.
美味しい？この面が美味しかったら、食べるんだったら中側がいいかも。
Delicious? If this part tastes good, the inside might be better to eat.
ちょっと進めていって。その中側。あ、でも、いや、こっちから団長が...
Let's move on. That inside... oh, but, no, from here I'll...
ここ掘るからさ、その中から、こうやって...
...dig here, so from the inside, like this...
ああ、大変だわ。
Oh, that's intense.
大変だな。でもあれだね、外側、外側ちょっと待った。
It's tough. But you know, the outside... wait, the outside...
あ、あのクリームさ、端っこの方に頑張って来ない？落ちないように頑張ってさ。
Hey, can we try to get to that cream on the edge? Let's try not to fall off.
そこからさ...
From there...
あ、わ！
Ah, wow!
えっ、うわー！
Eh, whoa!
ラミィ！危ない！
Lamy! Watch out!
あ、あかん。あかん。ファイト！
Ah, oh no. Oh no. Fight!
一発！
Ippatsu!
何なんでしょう。このステージにちょっと似つかわしくないファイト出してしまっているよ。
What is this? We're showing a "fight" spirit that doesn't really suit this stage.
危ない危ない。
Dangerous, dangerous.
じゃあちょっと、多分みんなもちょっと急すぎてさ、まだ付いてきてきてないよね。
Well, maybe everyone is a bit overwhelmed because it's so sudden, and they haven't caught up yet.
そうそう。
Right, right.
何を見せられているんだろうっていうね、多分。
Like, "what are we watching?" probably.
多分ね、スクショ撮るタイミングとかもちょっと分かってないから。今日はね、
They probably don't know when to take screenshots, so today,
ゲストさんにたくさん写真撮る機会を。
I'll give our guests plenty of chances to take photos.
おー、なるほど。
Oh, I see.
ツーショット撮ろうと思って。じゃあここ。
I thought we'd take some two-shots. So, here.
はい。
Yes.
せっかくだから。可愛い、いいですね。
Since we're here. Cute, it's nice.
あら、これさっきのね。
Oh, this is like before.
可愛い！あらたい、いいじゃないの。
Cute! Oh, this is great.
団長、もうこれはスクショはかどっちゃうのでは。
Dancho, this will really make people want to take screenshots.
ねえ、嬉しい。
Yeah, I'm glad.
あれ？でもやっぱ月の上がわに行ってるから...
Wait? But since we're on the moon...
団長、心なしかラミィよりもお姉さんに見える。
I feel like I look more like an older sister than Lamy.
確かに、背が高く見える。
True, you look taller.
ね、一緒なのに。あら。
Right, even though we're the same height. Oh.
いいわね。よしよし。あ、よしよし。
It's nice. There, there. Ah, there, there.
あ、まま...
Ah, Mama...
いや、まま。ちょっとラミィもままでしょうが。
No, Mama. But Lamy, you're a Mama too.
いやー、すごい写真撮った。あとね...
Man, we took a lot of photos. And also...
さっき気づいたんだけど。よいしょ。失礼失礼。よいしょ。
I just noticed this. Heave-ho. Excuse me. Heave-ho.
見て、ほら。
Look, see.
あ、これ！
Oh, this!
ブルンブルンブルン、バナナボート。
Vroom vroom vroom, banana boat.
バナナボートみたいでしょ。ブルンブルン。
It's like a banana boat, right? Vroom vroom.
多分ルーナたんもこの使われ方は多分想定してない気がするけど。ブルンブルン！
I don't think Luna-tan expected it to be used this way, though. Vroom vroom!
イエーイ！見てるー！
Yay! Are you watching?
写真撮ってね！横からも、こんな感じで。
Take photos! From the side too, like this.
撮ります！ブーンブーンブーン！
We're taking them! Vroom vroom vroom!
イエーイ！
Yay!
やばいな。この流れで実はね、団長...
Oh boy. And in this flow, actually, I...
今回このライブ、ゲストさん最後なんです。ラミィで。
For this live, this is the last guest. With Lamy.
は！なるほど。
Ha! I see.
そう、ここから団長ソロで、ちょっとまた頑張るんですけど。
Yes, from here I'll be solo and will do my best again.
がんばって〜、楽しみ。
Good luck~ I'm looking forward to it.
本当特等席で見てて。
Really, watch from the best seat.
今ね、あのゲストに出てくれた人はあのセンターでみんな見てるんだけど。
Right now, the guests who appeared are all watching from the center.
あ、でもここでラミィも...
Ah, but here, Lamy too...
そう、ラミィも一緒にあそこに一緒に見てほしい。
Yeah, I want Lamy to watch together from there too.
やったー、見ます！
Yay, I'll watch!
じゃあ、この、これでいくか。
Then, let's go with this.
これで行きます？
Are we going with this?
これで。後ろに出で出てもいいよ、団長一生懸命やるから。
With this. You can even come out in the back, Danchou will do her best.
じゃあ、行くぜ！
Alright, let's go!
ブンブンブンブン！次のステージまで行くぜ！ブンブンブン！
Vroom vroom! Heading to the next stage! Vroom vroom!
ウワァァァァ！ブーン！ブルルン、ブルルン...
Waaaaah! Vroooom! Vroom, vroom...
One, two, three, four!
一つ数えて進めばいい
Just count one and move forward
二つ数えて休めばいい
Just count two and take a rest
三つ数えて考えりゃいい
Just count three and think about it
マイペースで進めばいい
Just move forward at your own pace
時が流れ 取り残され
Time flows by, leaving you behind
焦る気持ちを 忘れるなかれ
Don't forget those feelings of impatience
無謀な挑戦 所詮無駄と
Reckless challenges are just a waste
言われて諦めることなかれ
Don't let them say that and make you give up
Oh face 苦しい時にこそ声を
Oh face, especially when it's tough
出していこう
Let's raise our voices
Oh face 自分が目指してる方へ
Oh face, towards the direction you're aiming for
向かえ
Head forth
そびえ立った大きな壁に
Before the great wall towering above
恐れることはない
There is nothing to fear
答えのないこの人生を
In this life without answers
迷うことなく
Without hesitation
一つ数えて進めばいい
Just count one and move forward
二つ数えて休めばいい
Just count two and take a rest
三つ数えて考えりゃいい
Just count three and think about it
マイペースで進めばいい
Just move forward at your own pace
やばい、やばい、焦れ焦れ！マイペースになってなかった！焦れ焦れ！
Oh no, oh no, hurry hurry! I wasn't going at my own pace! Hurry hurry!
学ぶことの本当の理由
The real reason for learning
分からず失う僕らの自由
Losing our freedom without knowing why
臆病者と呼ばれても
Even if you're called a coward
一歩譲れる それが勇気
Being able to step back, that's courage
Oh face 周りなど気にせず声を
Oh face, without worrying about others
出していこう
Let's raise our voices
Oh face 肩の力を抜いて
Oh face, relax your shoulders
さあ向かおう
Now, let's head forth
空に描いた未来には
To the future drawn in the sky
今は届かなくても
Even if we can't reach it now
いつの日にか 両手を伸ばし
Someday, stretching out both hands
掴みに行こう
Let's go and grasp it
It's my pace!
Oh face できるだけ大きな声を
Oh face, with the loudest voice possible
出してみよう
Let's try to shout
Oh face 自分が目指してる方へ
Oh face, towards the direction you're aiming for
向かえ
Head forth
そびえ立った大きな壁に
Before the great wall towering above
恐れることはない
There is nothing to fear
叶わないと逃げていても
Even if you run away saying it won't come true
変わりはいない
Nothing will change
響き渡る始まりの鐘
The bell of beginning ringing out
今 立ち上がる時
Now is the time to stand up
答えのないこの人生を
In this life without answers
迷うことなく
Without hesitation
It's my pace
一つ数えて進めばいい
Just count one and move forward
二つ数えて休めばいい
Just count two and take a rest
三つ数えて考えりゃいい
Just count three and think about it
マイペースで進めばいい
Just move forward at your own pace
みんなお待たせー！
Everyone, thanks for waiting!
ちょっと団長、アイドル衣装にお着替えしてきました！
I've changed into my idol outfit!
今日は2周年ライブ、いっぱい見てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for watching my 2nd anniversary live!
ゲストさんもね、出演してくれてありがとうございます！
And thanks to the guests for appearing too!
いや、もうね、すごい楽しいライブになったんですが、
It's been such a fun live,
今回まだね、あと一曲、このアイドル衣装で歌いたい曲があって、
but there's still one more song I want to sing in this idol outfit.
あの、団長重大告知と、ま、この配信重大告知ありますよって言ったから、
I said there'd be a big announcement for this stream,
みんなソワソワ、ワクワクしてるんじゃないかなと思います。
so I think everyone's feeling restless and excited.
ちょっとね、団長ね、ま、ちょっとあの、私事になりますが、なんと、なんと！
So, this is a bit of personal news, but... believe it or not!
歌ってみたも、オリ曲も、今まで出したことなくて、
I've never released a cover song or an original song before.
あの、団長はね、ま、3期生でも唯一オリ曲を出しておらず、
I was the only one in the 3rd gen without an original song,
もうマリンにいたっては2曲目入って、「やべぇ、団長もオリ曲出したいな」という話をずっとしてたんですけど、
while Marine is already on her second. I kept saying, "Man, I want to release an original song too."
ま、ここまで言えばみんなわかると思いますが、なななんと、
By now, I'm sure you've guessed, but...
最後の一曲は、団長オリ曲を歌わせていただきます！
for the final song, I'll be singing my own original song!
9月26日 24時 配信開始
9/26 24:00 Distribution Starts
今回ね、なんとオリ曲、作成していただきました！
I've had an original song created for me!
で、あの作詞・作曲の方なんですけど、
As for the composer and lyricist...
あの、ま、このライブを見てたらね、もしかしたら気づいた人は気づいたかもしれません。
if you've been watching this live, you might have noticed.
あの、『コネクト』『ルミナス』というね、とても素敵な曲を作っている
Sho Watanabe, who wrote the wonderful songs
渡辺翔さんが今回、『ほめのび』という曲を作ってくれました！本当にありがとうございます！
'Connect' and 'Luminous', wrote this song called 'Homenobi'! Thank you so much!
もう団長大好きなね、あの作詞・作曲家さんなので、本当に嬉しいです。
He's a creator I really love, so I'm so happy.
この曲をみんなにね、今ライブを見てるみんなに一番に聴いてほしいので、団長、心を込めて歌わせていただきます。
I want everyone watching the live to be the first to hear it, so I'll sing it with all my heart.
ま、ここに書いてある通り、このあとね、配信が終わったあとにミュージックビデオが公開されて、
As shown here, the music video will be released after this stream,
そのあと楽曲も配信されますので、何卒そちらもよろしくお願いします。
and the song will be available on streaming services, so please check them out.
では、2周年ライブありがとうございました！
Well then, thank you for the 2nd anniversary live!
これからもたくさん活動頑張っていきますので、よろしくお願いします。では、気持ちを込めてオリ曲歌わせていただきます。
I'll keep working hard, so please continue to support me. Now, I'll sing my original song with all my heart.
聴いてください、ほめのび！
Please listen: Homenobi!
ほめのび
作詞・作曲・編曲　渡辺翔
Homenobi
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Sho Watanabe
毎日おかわり練習中
Practicing for an encore every day
しれっとこそこそ準備進行
Secretly and stealthily making preparations
心境、緊張、であせる
The state of mind, the tension, I'm panicking
言わんけどつよつよアリでしょう
I won't say it, but being strong is good, right?
元気配るから待ってて
I'll spread some energy, so just wait
そうやって成長する子です
That's the kind of person who grows
いいかな？
Is it okay?
ゆるぼんでOK
Relaxed is OK
1、2、3、ピンパチャってOK
1, 2, 3, a quick snap is OK
始めちゃおう
Let's get started
褒めてほしいな　褒めてほしいな
I want to be praised, I want to be praised
褒めてくれたら2割増しで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder
見ててほしいな　見ててほしいな
I want you to watch, I want you to watch
褒めちぎられて伸びるタイプです　もう！
I'm the type who grows from being praised! Jeez!
何にも出てこない
Nothing's coming out
頭ん中真っ白だ　さっぱりだ
My mind's a total blank, I'm clueless
うんうん　あれ？　まあいいか！
Uh-huh, wait, what? Well, whatever!
でこぼこな情緒提供中
Currently providing bumpy emotions
ポカンとして何しよんの？
Staring blankly, what are you doing?
こんなんが通常の私
This is the usual me
いいでしょ？
Isn't it fine?
それではOK
Then it's OK
1、2、3、おちつきOK
1, 2, 3, calm down, it's OK
始めちゃおう
Let's get started
どうしたらいいの？　どうしたらいいの？
What should I do? What should I do?
どうすればみんなハッピーで笑顔バッチリ
How can I make everyone happy and smiling perfectly?
こちらへどうぞ　こちらへどうぞ
This way, please; this way, please
お茶ず慌てず並んで合図です　もう！
Without tea or rushing, line up for the signal! Jeez!
聞こえてる？
Can you hear me?
にゃんにゃんにゃん
Nyan nyan nyan
楽しんでる？
Are you having fun?
にゃんにゃんにゃん
Nyan nyan nyan
こっちだよ！
Over here!
少し眠いの
I'm a little sleepy
また明日食べて寝て
Eat and sleep again tomorrow
今は成長期
I'm in a growth period now
夢を見たいな
I want to dream
どうぞくれぐれも あの今後も
Please, by all means, from now on too
褒めてほしいな
I want to be praised
褒めてくれたら 2割増しで
If you praise me, I'll work
頑張る見ててほしいな
20% harder, I want you to watch me
見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me
褒めちぎられて 伸びるタイプです
I'm the type who grows by being showered with praise
またね！
See you later!
白銀ノエル
まだまだお楽しみはこれから！
Shirogane Noel
The fun is just beginning!
10月4日(月) 21:00～ (JST)
新衣装お披露目
October 4th (Mon) 21:00~ (JST)
New Outfit Reveal